<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Creation of a Cross-tab Report">
  <intro>
    <description>This tutorial helps you create a cross-tab inside a BIRT report
    </description>
  </intro>
  <item
  		title="Build a Data Source" skip="true">
     <description>In Data Explorer, right-click Data Sources and choose New Data Source.<br/>
     - On New Data Source, Classic Models Inc. Sample Database is selected. Choose Next.<br/>
     - Choose Finish.
     </description>
     <action class="org.eclipse.birt.report.designer.data.ui.actions.NewDataSourceAction"
     pluginId="org.eclipse.birt.report.designer.ui.data"/>
  </item>
  <item
  		title="Build a Data Set" skip="true">
     <description>- In Data Explorer, right-click Data Sets and choose New Data Set.<br/>
      - On New Data Set, choose Next.<br/>
      - On Query, in Available Items, expand one or more tables in the ClassicModels database.<br/>
      - To create a SQL query, drag column names from Available Items to the right pane to write the SELECT and FROM clauses. Then, choose Finish.<br/>
      - On Edit Data Set, select Preview Results. Then, choose OK.
     </description>
     <action class="org.eclipse.birt.report.designer.data.ui.actions.NewDataSetAction"
     pluginId="org.eclipse.birt.report.designer.ui.data"/>
  </item>
  <item
  		title="Set up data for the cross tab" skip="true">
     <description>- In Data Explorer, right-click Data Cubes and choose New Data Cube.<br/>
      - In Data Set Selection, in Primary Data set, select the data set that you just created. Then, choose Groups and Summaries.<br/>
      - In Groups and Summaries, drag fields to create Groups (Dimensions) and Summary Fields (Measures).<br/>
      - Choose OK.
      </description>
  </item>
  <item
  		title="Add a cross tab to the report" skip="true">
  	 <description>- In the layout editor, double-click the template cross-tab element to enable editing.<br/>
         - Drag group fields from the data cube into row and column cells in the cross tab.<br/>
         - Drag summary fields from the data cube into the fields to be summarized cell in the cross tab.
         </description>
   </item>
  <item
  		title="Add grand totals" skip="true">
  	 <description>In the layout editor, select the cross tab.
         In the property editor, add totals to the Row Area and Column Area in Sub Totals and Grand Totals.</description>
   </item>
</cheatsheet>
