<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?NLS type="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>

<contexts>
<context id="dummy_outer_container" title="BIRT contexts">
<description>Contexts for items identified by Actuate, 09/2008</description>
</context>

<context id="NewReportProjectWizard_ID" title="New Report Project">
<description>
Use this dialog box to specify a project name for the new report project. For the project contents, you can either choose the default location or specify an alternate location.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.2.html" label="Building a simple listing report"/>
</context>

<context id="NewReportWizard_ID" title="New Report - Create a new report">
<description>
Use this page to specify a parent folder and a file name for a new report.

If you created a project for the new report, you can select it as the parent folder.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.2.html" label="Building a simple listing report"/>
</context>

<context id="NewReportCopyWizard_ID" title="New Report - Select a report to copy">
<description>
Use this page to select a blank report, one of the report templates that are provided with the copy, or a previously created report, and then choose <b>Finish</b>.

When you highlight a report template, a preview of the report is displayed to the right.

If you select Show Report Creation Cheat Sheet, the corresponding cheat sheet is displayed, if one is available, when you choose <b>Finish</b>.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.2.html" label="Building a simple listing report"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_NewDataSource_ID" title="New Data Source - Select a Data Source Type or Choose a Connection Profile">
<description>
Use this page to select the type of data source that you want to include in your report, and then specify the name of the data source.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.2.html" label="Building a simple listing report"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_Dataset_ID" title="New Data Set">
<description>
Use this page to specify the data set properties:

 - In Data Set Name, specify a name for the data set. The data-set name must be unique in the report design.
 - In Data Source, use the drop-down list to choose a data source for this data set.
 - In Data Set Type, select a data-set type.

A <b>data set</b> is a query that specifies the data to retrieve from the data source.

The data set type indicates the type of query. For example, if your report connects to a JDBC data source, you use a SQL SELECT statement to specify the data to retrieve.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.1.html" label="How to create a BIRT data source"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.1.html" label="Connecting to a Data Source"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_SQLQuery_Dataset_ID" title="New SQL Select Query">
<description>Use this page to create the SQL Select query that specifies what data to retrieve from the database. Use the middle pane to select tables and columns, and to join tables. Use the items in the lower pane to specify the following: how to sort data, what subset of the data to retrieve, what data to group for aggregations, and the criteria for returning specific aggregate data. Based on the selections you make in these panes, the top pane displays the SQL Select statement. 
</description>
</context>


<context id="Wizard_DatasourceProfile_ID" title="Data Source Profile">
<description>
This screen displays a profile of the selected database.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.1.html" label="How to create a BIRT data source"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_JDBC_Datasource_ID" title="New JDBC Data Source Profile">
<description>
Use this dialog box to define a new JDBC data source.

  - In Driver Class, choose an available driver from the drop-down list. This specifies the brand of database you use.
  - In Database URL, type the URL for the machine that runs the database.
  - In User Name, type the user name you use to access the database.
  - In Password, type the Password for the user name.
  - In JNDI URL, type the URL for the JNDI database service used to retrieve a pooled connection.

Choose Manage Drivers to add, remove, or change the drivers in the Driver Class drop-down list.

Choose Test Connection to get diagnostic information about the connection to the Database URL you specify in the Database URL field.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.3.html" label="How to specify the connection information for a database or other JDBC data source"/>
</context>

<context id="Dialog_JDBC_ManageDrivers_ID" title="Manage JDBC Drivers">
<description>
Use this dialog box to manage the available JDBC drivers and to add new ones.

Use the JARs tab to manage library files.

Use the Drivers tab to specify driver details.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.4.html" label="How to add a JDBC driver"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_XML_Datasource_ID" title="New XML File Data Source Profile">
<description>
Use this dialog box to define an XML file data source.

Choose Test Connection to get diagnostic information about the connection to the URL you specify for the XML Source File.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.1.html" label="Retrieving Data"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_FlatfileDatasource_ID" title="New Flat File Data Source Profile">
<description>
Use this dialog box to define the profile for a new flat file.

 - In Select folder, choose the folder to contain flat file data sources. 
 - In Select charset, select the character encoding of the flat file from the drop-down list. 
 - In User Name, type the user name you use to access the database. 
 - In Select flatfile style, choose the delimiter style for the data fields: 
     CSV = Comma Delimited.
     SSV = Semicolon delimited.
     TSV = Tab delimited.
     PSV = Pipe delimited.
 - In JNDI URL, type the URL for the JNDI name you use to access the database.

Choose Test Connection to get diagnostic information about the connection to the folder you specify in the Select folder field.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.1.html" label="Retrieving Data"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.2.html" label="Working with Data Sources"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_ConnectionProfile_ID" title="New Data Source - Select a Connection Profile">
<description>
Use this dialog box to select a connection profile for creating a data source.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.1.html" label="Retrieving Data"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_JDBCDataset_ID" title="Query">
<description>
Use this dialog box to define a SQL query.

The Available Items allows you to browse data sets and expand tables, fields, and functions available from that data set.  Double clicking an item from this list adds it to the text of the query on the right side of the dialog.

Inspect and edit the query text in the text field on the right side of the dialog.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.2.html" label="How to create a data set"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.2.html#203768" label="How to create a SQL query for a JDBC data set"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_XMLSample_ID" title="XML Data Set">
<description>
Use this dialog box to specify a sample XML source for data preview.

Deselect Use the XML File defined in Data Source to use a different xml data source file.

Select Preview first to specify a number of records to display in the preview.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.1.html" label="Retrieving Data"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_XMLXPath_ID" title="Table Mapping">
<description>
Use this dialog box to map a table.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.4.html" label="How to bind a data set to a table"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.html#139187" label="How to merge table or grid cells"/>
</context>

<context id="Dialog_XPathExpression_ID" title="Select or edit the XPath expression">
<description>
Use this dialog box to specify the XPath expression to use.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_XML_ColumnMapping_ID" title="Column Mapping">
<description>
Use this page to map XML elements to columns.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/birt/retrieving-data.3.5.html" label="How to view and change output columns"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/data_binding.4.2.html" label="How to create a column binding"/>
</context>

<context id="Dialog_ColumnMapping_ID" title="Column Mapping">
<description>
Use this dialog box to map a column to an XPath expression.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.5.html" label="How to view and change output columns"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.2.html" label="How to create a column binding"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_ScriptDataset_ID" title="New Data Set - Output columns">
<description>
Use this page to define output columns.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.5.html" label="How to view and change output columns"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.2.html" label="How to create a column binding"/>
</context>

<context id="Dialog_SelectTableColumn_ID" title="Select Table - Select Column">
<description>
Use this dialog box to select columns for the data set.
</description>

<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.2.html" label="How to create a data set"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/retrieving-data.3.7.html" label="How to join data sets"/>
</context>

<context id="Dialog_JDBCDriver_ID" title="Edit JDBC Drivers">
<description>
Use this dialog box to specify the JDBC driver properties for display.

Type a name and the syntax suggestion to display for this driver in the driver manager and New Data Source, respectively.
</description>

<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/connecting.2.2.html#191398" label="How to add a JDBC driver"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_JointDataSet_ID" title="New Data Set - Joint Data Set">
<description>
Use this page to define a joint data set by associating data sets and columns.

Select the columns to join. Select one column from the first data set and one column from the second data set.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.2.html" label="How to create a data set"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/retrieving-data.3.7.html" label="How to join data sets"/>

</context>

<context id="Dialog_DatasourceEdit_ID" title="Edit Data Source - Data Source">
<description>
Use this dialog box to provide URLs for the data source and schema.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.1.html" label="Connecting to a Data Source"/>
</context>

<context id="Dialog_DatasetEdit_ID" title="Edit Data Set - Data Set">
<description>
Use this dialog box to define the attributes of a data set.

A <b>data set</b> is a query that specifies the data to retrieve from the data source.

Select one of the following items in the left pane of the dialog box to:

  - Query - specify the data to retrieve.
  - Data Source - change the data source you specified in the <b>New Data Set</b> dialog box.
  - Preview - display a preview of the items that you selected in your query.
  - Computed Columns - add computed fields to an existing data set.
  - Parameters - create data set parameters.
  - Filters - define filters to be applied at the data-set level.
  - Output Columns - verify and change the columns to be output.
  - Property Binding - verify and change the binding of properties.
  - Cache Preference - set data-set caching options.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.1.html" label="Retrieving Data"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSourcePropertyBinding(org_eclipse_birt_report_data_oda_jdbc)_ID" title="Edit Data Source - JDBC Data Source - Property Binding">
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a JDBC data source. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Source. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

* JDBC Driver Class: Type an expression for the JDBC driver. This driver specifies the brand of database you use.
* JDBC Driver URL: Type an expression for the URL for the machine that runs the database.
* User Name: Type an expression for the user name you use to access the database.
* Password: Type an expression for the Password for the user name.
* JNDI URL: Type an expression for the URL for the JNDI name you use to access the database.
* Connection Profile Name: Type an expression for the name of the connection profile.
* Connection Profile Store URL: Type an expression for the URL to the location of the connection profile store.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSourcePropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_connectivity_oda_flatfile)_ID" title="Edit Data Source - Flat File Data Source - Property Binding">
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a flat file data source. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Source. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

* Home Folder: Type an expression for the path to a folder that contains the flat file to use as a data source.
* CSV Type: Type an expression for the data format. Valid values are:
  - CSV for comma-separated values
  - PSV for pipe-separated values
  - SSV for space-separated values
  - TSV for tab-separated values
* Character Set: Type an expression for the character set that the data values use.
* Use First Line as Column Name Indicator: Type an expression for a Boolean value. True indicates that the file provides data field names in its first line. False indicates that the first line does not contain data field names.
* Use Second Line as Data Type Indicator: If the value of Use First Line as Column Name Indicator is false, this field applies to the first line of the flat file, rather than the second line. Type an expression for a Boolean value. True indicates that the file provides data types for the data fields. False indicates that the line does not contain data field types.
* Connection Profile Name: Type an expression for the name of the connection profile.
* Connection Profile Store URL: Type an expression for the URL to the location of the connection profile store.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSourcePropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_enablement_oda_ws)_ID" title="Edit Data Source - Web Service Data Source - Property Binding">
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a web service data source. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Source. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

* SOAP End Point: Leave this field empty if the descriptor defines the end point or if the WSDL does not require a SOAP end point. If your WSDL does require a SOAP end point, type an expression for the URL here.
* Connection Class: If you have written a Java class to perform the connection to and of the WSDL data source, type an expression for the fully qualified path to this class. This class must implement the <code>org.eclipse.datatools.enablement.oda.ws.api.IWSDriver</code> interface.
* Connection Time Out: Type an expression for the length of time, in seconds, to wait for the connection to succeed.
* WSDL URL: Type an expression for the URL for Web Services data that is a network resource.
* Driver ClassPath: If you have a custom driver class, type an expression to list the JAR files or folders to search for the class in Driver Class Path. Separate multiple folders and JAR files with semicolon (;) characters in the normal way.
* Connection Profile Name: Type an expression for the name of the connection profile.
* Connection Profile Store URL: Type an expression for the URL to the location of the connection profile store.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSourcePropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_enablement_oda_xml)_ID" title="Edit Data Source - XML Data Source - Property Binding">
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a XML data source. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Source. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

* XML Data Source File: Type an expression for the full name of the XML file to use as the data source.
* XML Data Source Encoding: Type an expression for the character encoding that the XML data uses.
* XML Data Source Schema File: Type an expression for the full name of the schema to use for the XML file.
* Connection Profile Name: Type an expression for the name of the connection profile.
* Connection Profile Store URL: Type an expression for the URL to the location of the connection profile store.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSetPropertyBinding(org_eclipse_birt_report_data_oda_jdbc)_ID" title="Edit Data Set - JDBC Data Set - Property Binding">
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a JDBC data set. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Set. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

* Query Text: Type an expression for the SQL statement for the query.
* Query Time Out: Type an expression for the length of time, in seconds, to wait for the query to return the first data row.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSetPropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_connectivity_oda_flatfile)_ID" title="Edit Data Set - Flat File Data Set - Property Binding">
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a flat file data set. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Set. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

In Query Text, type an expression for the query. Use the XML source tab in the Report Design Perspective to locate the QueryText element of an existing flat file data set. Use this element as a template for the required syntax.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSetPropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_enablement_oda_ws)_ID" title="Edit Data Set - Web Service Data Set - Property Binding">
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a web service data set. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Set. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

* Query Text: Type an expression for the SOAP request template for the query. Use the XML source tab in the Report Design Perspective to locate the QueryText element of an existing web service data set. Use this element as a template for the required syntax.
* XML File: Type an expression for the name of the XML file that contains sample data for the SOAP response.
* Schema File: Type an expression for the name of the XML schema file for the SOAP response on the file system.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSetPropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_enablement_oda_xml)_ID" title="Edit Data Set - XML Data Set - Property Binding">
<description>
An XML data set does not use any property binding values.
</description>
</context>

<context id="NewTemplateWizard_ID" title="New Template">
<description>
Use this wizard to define a new template for reports.

This type of file provides a structure for a standard report layout.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.1.html" label="Building a Shared Report Development Framework"/>
</context>

<context id="NewLibraryWizard_ID" title="New Library">
<description>
Use this page to specify a parent folder and a file name for a new library.

This type of file stores customized report elements such as data sources, data sets, visual report items, and styles. Include a library in a report design to access the customized report elements.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.1.html" label="Building a Shared Report Development Framework"/>
</context>

<context id="SaveReportAsWizard_ID" title="Save as">
<description>
Use this dialog box to specify the filename and location of the file that you are saving.
</description>
</context>

<context id="PublishTemplateWizard_ID" title="Template properties">
<description>
Use this dialog box to specify file name, description, and template image for a template.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.1.html" label="Building a Shared Report Development Framework"/>
</context>

<context id="FormatBuilder_ID" title="Format Builder">
<description>
Use this dialog box to control the formatting of strings.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/format.html" label="Formatting Report Content"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/ChartFormatting.16.1.html" label="Laying Out and Formatting a Chart"/>

</context>

<context id="ImportValueDialog_ID" title="Import Values">
<description>
Use this dialog box to import values into your report.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.13.html" label="Provide the option to select all vendors"/>

</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderGeneral_ID" title="New Style - General Page">
<description>
Use this page to apply a style to the report element that you selected in the layout editor. Also, use this page to define a new style.

On the General page, specify one of the following settings:
 - To apply an existing set of style properties to the report element, select <b>Predefined Style</b> and select a style from the drop-down list.
 - To create a user-named style, specify a unique descriptive name for <b>Custom Style</b>. Do not use any of the predefined style names. If you specify a name that is the same as a predefined style, your custom style takes precedence, and you can no longer use the predefined style to apply cascading styles.

Note that the left side of this dialog box displays property categories. The right side displays the properties for the category that you select.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.2.html" label="How to create a style"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.5.html" label="How to apply a style"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.6.html" label="How to modify a style"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.7.html" label="How to delete a style"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.2.html" label="Building a simple listing report"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderFont_ID" title="New Style - Font Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify font information for the style.

Note that the left side of this dialog box displays property categories. The right side displays the properties for the category that you select.
</description>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderBackground_ID" title="New Style - Background Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify background information for the style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.2.html" label="Building a simple listing report"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderTextBlock_ID" title="New Style - Text Block Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify text block information for the style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.2.html" label="Building a simple listing report"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderBox_ID" title="New Style - Box Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify box information for the style.
</description>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderBorder_ID" title="New Style - Border Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify border information for the style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.2.html" label="Creating a cross tab"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderFormatNumber_ID" title="New Style - Format Number Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify number formatting for the style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/subreport.13.16.html#188035" label="Building a report with side-by-side subreports"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.10.html#222309" label="Change the number format"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderFormatDateTime_ID" title="New Style - Format Date Time Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify date and time formats for the style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/subreport.13.16.html#188035" label="Change the date formats"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderFormatString_ID" title="New Style - Format String Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify string format information for the style.
</description>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderPageBreak_ID" title="New Style - Page Break Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify page break information for the style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/multipage.html" label="Designing a Multipage Report"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderMap_ID" title="New Style - Map Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify map information for the style.
</description>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderHighlights_ID" title="New Style - Highlights Page">
<description>
Use this page to specify highlighting information for the style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/subreport.13.16.html#187991" label="Highlight the customer names"/>
</context>

<context id="ParameterGroupDialog_ID" title="New Parameter Group">
<description>
Use this dialog box to create a visual grouping of parameters.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.1.html" label="Enabling the User to Filter Data"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.1.html#258758" label="How to create a simple report parameter"/>
</context>

<context id="HyperlinkBuilder_ID" title="Hyperlink Options">
<description>
Use this page to define a link to another location.

You can define the following types of links:

  - A hyperlink to an external web site, e-mail system, and so forth. The Hyperlink property returns a standard web-style link with an http: or mailto: prefix. Expression hyperlinks can include special BIRT features, but only as encoded into a URL. If the link specifies a target within the document, encode that target within the URL as defined by target document type, as in the URL, <b>http://MyPage.com/docs/myDoc.html#myTarget</b>.

  - A bookmark to a location within the report as specified by a bookmark. Use the Bookmark property of a report item to create the target bookmark.

  - A drill-though to a location within another report as specified by a bookmark. The drill-though link can link to an existing report, or request to run a new report. It can optionally include:

    - Parameters to pass when creating a new report
    - A location within the target report as specified by a search
    - A location within the target report as specified by a bookmark
    - An output format for the linked report
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/viewing.19.1.html" label="Adding Interactive Viewing Features"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/viewing.19.3.html" label="How to link two report sections"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/viewing.19.4.html" label="How to link two reports"/>
</context>

<context id="ExpressionBuilder_ID" title="Expression Builder">
<description>
Use this dialog box to create expressions for any purpose that your report requires.

For example, you can create a computed field in your report layout or an aggregate expression to display summary information.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/aggregate.html" label="Aggregating Data"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/expressions.html" label="Writing Expressions"/>
</context>

<context id="ParameterDialog_ID" title="New Parameter">
<description>Use this dialog box to create a report parameter to enable a user to filter data in your report. The report parameter prompts a user to specify values that determine the data rows to retrieve.

Specify the following basic properties:

 - For Name, type a name for the parameter. If you do not specify a value for Prompt text, the report user sees the Name value as the parameter prompt.
 - For Type, select a data type for the parameter. The data type you select does not have to match the data type of the field in the data source. For example, values in an orderID field are stored as integers in the database, but the report parameter associated with this field is of type decimal or string. The data type you select for the report parameter determines the formatting options available. You can choose to provide a default value or a list of values for the report parameter.

For date fields, you can select either Date Time or String data type. Specifying the String data type provides more flexibility for the user to specify dates in a variety of formats. The user can type, for example, 02/04/2004, 2/4/04, or Feb 4, 2004. A limitation is that you cannot use date and time formats to change how dates appear if you choose to provide the user with a list of date values.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.1.html" label="Enabling the User to Filter Data"/>
</context>

<context id="CascadingParametersDialog_ID" title="New Cascading Parameter">
<description>
Use this dialog box to define a cascading parameter group.

A parameter group is a visual grouping of dynamic parameters. When the value of a particular parameter in the group depends on the value of another parameter, the parameter group is a cascading parameter group.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.1.html" label="Enabling the User to Filter Data"/>
</context>

<context id="ImageBuilder_ID" title="New Image Item">
<description>
Use this dialog box to insert an image directly on the page or into any container element.

To insert a linked image, select the <b>URI</b> radio button. In Enter URI, specify the location of the image file. Enclose the URI in double quotation marks (" ").

To insert an image file from a shared resource, select the <b>Image file in shared resources</b> radio button. For Enter resource file, choose Browse, and then specify the location of the image file.

To insert an embedded image, select the <b>Embedded image</b> radio button, and then choose <b>Add Image</b> to select the image that you want to embed.

Typically, you insert data source images in the detail row of a table to display all the pictures stored in the data source. To insert an image that is stored in a data source, select the <b>Dynamic image</b> radio button, and then choose <b>Select Image Data</b> to specify the field in the data set.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.5.html" label="How to insert a linked image"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.6.html" label="How to insert an embedded image"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/layout.5.7.html" label="How to insert images that are stored in a data source"/>
</context>

<context id="TableOptionDialog_ID" title="Insert Table or Grid">
<description>
Use this dialog box to insert a Table element.

You can specify the number of columns, the number of detail rows, and the data set from which the table retrieves data.

A Table element presents data from a data set using a tabular layout that displays the following content:

 - The header appears at the top of the table and on each new page. Typically, the header contains labels for the data values in the columns. 
 - The optional columns property defines the columns. 
 - Optional groups. To specify a group, right-click in the table and choose <b>Insert Group - Above</b> or <b>Insert Group - Below</b>. In New Group, specify the group. 
 - The footer displays totals and appears at the bottom of the table. The detail appears for every row in the data set.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.2.html" label="How to add a row or column"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.3.html" label="How to delete a row or column"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.11.html" label="How to resize a column or row by dragging its boundary"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.12.html" label="How to specify a row height"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.13.html" label="How to specify a column width"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.14.html" label="How to merge table or grid cells"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.4.html" label="How to bind a data set to a table"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/grouping.8.1.html" label="Sorting and Grouping Data"/>
</context>

<context id="GridOptionDialog_ID" title="Insert Grid">
<description>
Use this dialog box to insert a Grid element.

Use a grid to arrange static elements, such as text and images, within a section.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.11.html" label="How to resize a column or row by dragging its boundary"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.12.html" label="How to specify a row height"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.13.html" label="How to specify a column width"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.14.html" label="How to merge table or grid cells"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.5.html" label="How to insert a linked image"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.6.html" label="How to insert an embedded image"/>
</context>

<context id="TextEditor_ID" title="Edit Text Item">
<description>
Use this dialog box to edit and format a Text element.

The Text element displays a multi-line block of text defined within the report. This element can contain embedded formatting and value expressions.

The report developer uses the Text item to add text to the report design. Text can be localized and in either HTML or plain text format. HTML text can contain placeholders for data and expressions, much like the mail merge feature of a word processing program.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/text.6.1.html" label="Displaying Text"/>
</context>
<context id="GroupDialog_ID" title="New Group">
<description>
Use this dialog box to define and configure groups.

Grouping data in a report can make the data easier to interpret and use. For example, you can group customer data by credit limit.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/grouping.8.1.html" label="Sorting and Grouping Data"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/grouping.8.2.html" label="Tutorial 2: Grouping report data"/>
</context>

<context id="DataBindingDialog_ID" title="Select Data Binding">
<description>
Use this dialog box to bind data columns or expressions to names.

As well as selecting the appropriate data set and column, you can define calculated fields that items inside a list or table can use.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.1.html" label="Binding Data"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.2.html" label="How to create a column binding"/>
</context>

<context id="HighlightRuleBuilder_ID" title="New Highlight">
<description>
Use this dialog box to specify the condition, or rule, for applying a particular format to a report element.

The dialog box helps you specify the If and Then parts of a rule by breaking them down into more specific parts.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.html" label="Formatting Report Content"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.8.html" label="How to create a formatting rule"/>
</context>

<context id="Preference_BIRT_BIDI_ID" title="Preferences - Bidirectional Properties page">
<description>Use this page to set the default layout direction for new report designs.

The setting, Left to Right, is suitable for designing reports in languages such as English or Russian that write text from the left of the page to the right. The setting, Right to Left, is suitable for languages such as Arabic or Hebrew that write in the opposite direction.

For example:
When the report orientation is left to right:
* The handles for table, grid, and cross-tab rows appear on the left of the element in the layout editor.
* When you drag a data set into the layout, the data columns are added from the left of the table to the right.
* Scroll bars appear on the right edge of the layout editor windows.

When the report orientation is right to left:
* The handles for table, grid, and cross-tab rows appear on the right of the element in the layout editor.
* When you drag a data set into the layout, the data columns are added from the right of the table to the left.
* Scroll bars appear on the left edge of the layout editor windows.
</description>
</context>


<context id="Preference_Chart_Content_Assist_ID" title="Preferences - Chart Content Assist page">
<description>Use this page to control the behavior of the content assist tool in the chart builder. Content assist is available in fields for which you supply an expression. Use it to insert an expression in a field.
</description>
</context>


<context id="Preference_Chart_Field_Assist_ID" title="Preferences - Chart Field Assist page">
<description>Use this page to control the behavior of field assist in the chart builder. You can choose whether or not to identify required fields with a symbol. You can also specify the position of the symbol relative to the field.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Preference_BIRT_DataSetEditor_ID" title="Preferences - Data Set Editor page">
<description>Use this page to control how the Data Set Editor displays SQL queries and report previews.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.1.html" label="Retrieving data"/>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_ElementNames_ID" title="Preferences - Element Names page">
<description>Use this page to assign default names to elements of the Report Object Model (ROM).
</description>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_Library_ID" title="Preferences - Library page">
<description>Use this page to add or remove libraries.

A BIRT report library is a collection of report components that can be used in a report design. Report components include reusable visual report items, data sources, data sets, parameters, translations and more.

A library is a customizable, pre-defined set of rules that helps a user quickly create a report with a specific look.

A BIRT library includes both formatting information and rules that help you create a report. A library is like a skin for a report; it takes the data, structure, and layout of a report, and applies formatting defined in the library to transform the appearance of the report.

A library can start with a style sheet, a set of common styles to apply to all reports within an application. The library can then add commonly used data sources, reusable components, translated text, images and more.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.1.html20" label="Shared Report Development"/>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_Preview_ID" title="Preferences - Preview page">
<description>Use this page to control how reports are previewed in web browsers.

To add a browser, select Custom Browser and type the command to open it.

You can enable an SVG device renderer for the chart engine. This reference implementation (located in the org.eclipse.birt.chart.device.svg plug-in) defines basic SVG drawing primitives based on the SVG 1.1 specification.
</description>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_PreviewServer_ID" title="Preferences - Preview Server page">
<description>Use this page to set up an internal application server to preview your reports.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.wst.server.ui.doc.user" href="../org.eclipse.wst.server.ui.doc.user/topics/twcrtins.html" label="Internal Application Server"/>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_Template_ID" title="Preferences - Template page">
<description>Use this page to specify the folder that contains your templates.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.5.html" label="How to set up a template folder"/>
</context>


<context id="ImportCssStyle_ID" title="Import CSS Styles">
<description>Use this dialog box to import CSS styles into your report design.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt/format.7.3.html" label="How to import styles"/>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_CommentTemplate_ID" title="Preferences - Comment Template">
<description>Use this page to add a comment to a report design.
</description>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_Resource_ID" title="Preferences - Resource">
<description>Use this page to select the default Resource Folder for the localized text files and the Library Explorer.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/localization.21.1.html" label="Localizing text"/>
</context>


<context id="PublishLibraryDialog_ID" title="Publish Library">
<description>Use this dialog box to publish a library to a resource folder.

Publishing a library makes it available for reuse.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.4.html" label="How to add an element to a library"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.1.html" label="Building a Shared Report Development Framework"/>
</context>

<context id="ResourceSelectDialog_ID" title="Browse resource folders">
<description>Use this dialog box to select the resource folder to use for publishing the library.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.4.html" label="How to add an element to a library"/><topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.1.html" label="Building a shared report development framework"/>
</context>


<context id="ExportToLibrary_ID" title="Export">
<description>Use this dialog box to export a report design to a library.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.4.html" label="How to add an element to a library"/><topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.1.html" label="Building a shared report development framework"/>
</context>


<context id="CreateTemplateReportItem_ID" title="Create Template Report Item">
<description>Use this dialog box to define the properties of template report items.

Template report items are items that you intend report developers to modify for new report designs. Provide the necessary information about making modifications in the Instructions field.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.1.html" label="Building a shared report development framework"/>
</context>


<context id="AddEditMapRule_ID" title="New or Edit Map Rule">
<description>Use this dialog box to define map rules.

Map rules define the rules for mapping values in a database column to values in a report column. Each map rule contains a condition and a display value. For example, a set of map rules for a gender database column might map the values null, M, and F into display values No data, Male, and Female respectively.
</description>
</context>


<context id="AddEditUserProperties_ID" title="Add or Edit User Properties">
<description>Use this dialog box to specify user properties for BIRT classes.

User properties can provide indirect access to the BIRT JavaScript classes for BIRT event handlers written in Java code.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/ScriptingReference.html" label="Scripting reference"/>
</context>


<context id="AddEditNamedExpression_ID" title="New or Edit Named Expressions">
<description>Use this dialog box to define named expressions.

The name facilitates reuse.
</description>
</context>


<context id="ResourceEditDialog_ID" title="Property Editor - Localization">
<description>
Use this page to define localization properties.

To do this, choose the " <b>. . .</b> " button.

Note that you must assign a resource file to the report before you can define localization properties. The " <b>. . .</b> " button is not active until a resource file is assigned.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/localization.21.1.html" label="Localizing text"/>
</context>


<context id="AddLibraryDialog_ID" title="Add Library">
<description>Use this dialog box to add a library to the resource folder.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.20.1.html" label="Building a shared report development framework"/>
</context>


<context id="AddResourceDialog_ID" title="Add Resource">
<description>Use this dialog box to add a shared resource, such as a library, an image, and a CSS file, to the resource folder. 
</description>
</context>


<context id="ColumnBindingDialog_ID" title="Select Data Binding">
<description>Use this dialog box to bind data to columns in a data set.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.1.html" label="Binding data"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/aggregate.html" label="Aggregating data"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.1.html" label="Enabling the user to filter data"/>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_DataSetEditor_JDBC_ID" title="Preferences - JDBC Data Set">
<description>Use this page to control the query page display.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.1.html" label="Retrieving data"/>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_DataSetEditor_XML_ID" title="Preferences - XML Data Set">
<description>Use this page to control the column mapping page.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.1.html" label="Retrieving data"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_CrossTab_ID">
   <description>Use this page to control the behavior of the crosstab editor.

In Filter Limit, specify the number of values to retrieve from the data source when selecting values for a filter.

In Prompt, select whether to display the informational message about how to create a crosstab element.

You can also choose how the report designer treats unused data bindings after you change the structure of a crosstab.</description>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_GENERAL_ID">
   <description>Use this page to set the appearance of a selected item in the report layout editor.

To display a selected item with an animated highlight, select Enable animated selection.

To display a selected item with a gradient highlight that is not animated, deselect Enable animated selection, then select Enable gradient selection.

To display a selected item with a simple outline with handles, deselect both Enable animated selection and Enable gradient selection.</description>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_Preview_DATA_ID">
   <description>Use this page to control the amount of data that a report displays in the Preview pane of the report designer. Reducing any of these values makes the report preview faster. Increasing these values produces a report preview that contains more of the data in your data set.

To set the maximum number of rows that the report preview fetches from the data set, type a value in Maximum number of rows to display.

To set the maximum number of rows to display in a group in a table or crosstab, type a value in  Maximum member count of each row level to display.

To set the maximum number of columns to display in a horizontal group in a crosstab, type a value in  Maximum member count of each column level to display.

To limit the size of a data cube structure in memory, type the number of megabytes in Maximum in-memory cube size.</description>
</context>


<context id="ParameterBindingDialog_ID" title="Dataset Parameter Binding">
<description>Use the dialog box to verify parameter bindings.

Use the Value column to check or change the report parameter to which the data set parameter is bound.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/subreport.13.10.html" label="Link the orders subreport to the customers master report"/>
</context>


<context id="NewSectionDialog_ID" title="Insert Element">
<description>Select an element to insert and choose OK.
</description>
</context>


<context id="DeleteWarningDialog_ID" title="Reference Found">
<description>BIRT Report Designer has analyzed your report design. Some report elements are using a report element that you selected to delete. This dialog lists the elements that other elements use. If you confirm that you want to delete them, you need to modify the elements that use them in order for your report to run.

To confirm deletion of the report element, choose Yes.
</description>
</context>


<context id="DimensionBuilderDialog_ID" title="Dimension Builder">
<description>In Measure, type the size of the property that you selected to edit.
In Units, select the unit of measure for the size.

To set these values, choose OK.
</description>
</context>


<context id="HandlerClassSelectionDialog_ID" title="Class Selection">
<description>This dialog shows the available event handlers that are appropriate to the report item that you currently selected in your report design.

Select the one that you need to get the event handling behavior that you want.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/UsingScripting.22.1.html" label="Using scripting in a report design"/>
</context>


<context id="NewResourceFileDialog_ID" title="Browse Resource Files">
<description>This dialog shows the available resource files in the BIRT resource folder.

Select the one that accesses the localized string values that you need.
</description>
</context>


<context id="AddJarResourceFileFolderSelectionDialog_ID" title="Browse Resource Files">
<description>
This dialog shows the available resource JAR files in the BIRT resource folder.

Select the one that accesses the set of localized string values that you need.
</description>
</context>


<context id="DataColumnBindingDialog_ID" title="Data Binding">
<description>
Use this dialog to bind a data expression to a name.
Data items use the name to display the result of the expression in a report.

The data expression can be a simple reference to a data field or a more complex calculation. To build an expression or access data fields, choose the builder button beside the expression field.
You also use this dialog to set the data type that the expression returns.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.1.html" label="Binding data"/>
</context>


<context id="DataItemBindingDialog_ID" title="Data Item">
<description>
Use this dialog to set the data expression for a data item.
The data expression can be a simple reference to a data field or a more complex calculation.

In Name, type a name for the expression. This name must be unique within a data set.
In Data Type, select the data type that the expression returns.
In Expression, type an expression. Alternatively, to build an expression or access data fields, choose the builder button beside the Expression field.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.2.html" label="How to create a column binding"/>
</context>


<context id="Dialog_PropertyHandle_ID" title="Computed Column/Filter/Parameter">
<description>
Use this dialog to set or modify a property of a data set.

To create a computed column, provide a name, data type, and expression. The column will be available to all report items that use this data set.

To create a filter, provide an expression to test, the test operator, and an expression that filters the test expression. Use this type of filter when the data source does not support the filtering in the query.

To create a parameter to filter the result set in a query, provide a name, data type, and direction. Direction can be Input, Output, or Input/Output. Only stored procedures support Output and Input/Output parameters. Provide a default value for the parameter or link it to a report parameter.
</description>
</context>


<context id="DataSetParameterBindingInputDialog_ID" title="Data Set Parameter Binding">
<description>
Use this dialog to modify the value that a data set parameter uses for this report item. For example, if a data set parameter takes its value from a report parameter that the user supplies, you can override that value in this dialog.

Type a new expression in Value. Alternatively, to build an expression or access data fields, choose the builder button beside the Value field.
</description>
</context>

<context id="AddEditSortkey_ID" title="Sort Key">
<description>
Use this dialog to create or edit a sort key for this report item.

In Key, select a data field to sort on from the drop-down menu.  Alternatively, you can use the expression builder to create a complex sorting condition.

In Direction, select ascending or descending to indicate how to sort the report item.
</description>
</context>

<context id="AddEditFilterCondition_ID" title="Filter Condition">
<description>
Use this dialog to create or edit a filter condition for this report item.

Select a data field as the filter from the drop-down menu, and then add a logical function and a value to filter by.
</description>
</context>

<context id="ThumbnailBuilder_ID" title="Thumbnail Builder">
<description>
Use this dialog to create or edit a thumbnail for your template.

Choose Generate from the report to produce an thumbnail that resembles the template Layout.

Choose Browse the file system to choose a thumbnail image from your file system.

Choose Import from shared resources to import a thumbnail image from your eclipse workspace, including the thumbnail for an existing template.
</description>
</context>

<context id="SelectionChoiceDialog_ID" title="">
<description>
Use this dialog to select the values for a static parameter of display type list box, combo box, or radio button.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.7.html" label="Static parameter example"/> 
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderDataSetSelectionPage_ID" title="Data Set Selection Page ">
<description>
Select a data set to go into the group or summary categories.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderGroupsPage_ID" title="Groups Page">
<description>
Create a group.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderLinkGroupsPage_ID" title="Link Groups Page">
<description>
Create a group link.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="LevelPropertyDialog_ID" title="Group Level Page">
<description>
Create a group level.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="MeasureDialog_ID" title="Summary Field Properties">
<description>
Create a summary.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="AddEditSubTotal_ID" title="Subtotal">
<description>
Add a subtotal to a row or column in a cross tab, or edit an existing subtotal.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="AddEditGrandTotal_ID" title="Grand Total">
<description>
Add a grand total to a row or column in a cross tab, or edit an existing grand total.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="AddEditPageBreakDialog_ID" title="Page Break">
<description>
Add a page break before or after a group level in a cross tab, or edit an existing page break definition.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CrossTabFilterConditionBuilder_ID" title="Filter Condition">
<description>
Use this dialog to create or edit a filter condition for a group level on a cross tab.

Select a data field as the filter from the drop-down menu, and then add a logical function and a value to filter by.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CrossTabSorterBuilder_ID" title="sort Key">
<description>
Use this dialog to create or edit a sort key for a group level on a cross tab.

In Key, select a data field to sort on from the drop-down menu.  Alternatively, you can use the expression builder to create a complex sorting condition.

In Direction, select ascending or descending to indicate how to sort the group.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CrossTabFilterSelectValueDialog_ID" title="Select Value">
<description>
Select a value from the list to filter the cross tab group.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CrossTabShowSummaryFieldDialog_ID" title="Show Summary Field">
<description>
Use this dialog to show or hide a summary field on a group level on a cross tab.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CrossTabLevelViewDialog_ID" title="Show Hide Group Level">
<description>
Use this dialog to show or hide a group level on a cross tab with a hierarchical dimension, such as year, quarter, month.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CrossTabAggregationDialog_ID" title="Aggregation Builder">
<description>
Use this dialog to build or modify an aggregate expression.
- In Display Name, type the display name.
- In Data Type, select the type of the data to display.
- In Function, select the aggregation function.
- In Data Field, select the field on which to aggregate.
- In Filter Condition, type an expression to select the rows to aggregate.
- In Aggregate On, select a grouping level.
Choose OK.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/aggregate.html" label="Aggregating Data"/>
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderGroupDialog_ID" title="Group Level">
<description>
set or modify the properties of the group.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderDateLevelDialog_ID" title="Group Level">
<description>
Set or modify the properties of a date time group.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderFilterListDialog_ID" title="Filter">
<description>
Use this dialog to create or edit a filter condition for the data set rows that the cube uses.

Select a data field as the filter from the drop-down menu, and then add a logical function and a value to filter by.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.1.html" label="Presenting Data in a Cross Tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="AddCSSDialog_ID" title="Add CSS File">
<description>
Add a cascading style sheet (CSS) file as a resource.
- In Source File, type or browse to an existing CSS file.
- In File Name, accept the default or type a new name to save the file in the project.
- In Folder, browse to a folder to save the CSS file.
Choose Finish.
</description>
</context>

<context id="PublishCSSDialog_ID" title="Publish CSS File">
<description>
Publish a cascading style sheet (CSS) file to the resource folder.
</description>
</context>

<context id="UseCssInReportDialog_ID" title="Use CSS">
<description>
Select a cascading style sheet (CSS) file to use in the report design. The valid CSS styles are displayed in Available styles. CSS styles that BIRT cannot use are displayed in Notifications.
</description>
</context>

</contexts>
