<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?NLS type="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>

<contexts>
<context id="dummy_outer_container" title="BIRT contexts">
<description>Contexts for items identified by Actuate, 06/2009</description>
</context>

<context id="NewReportProjectWizard_ID" title="New Report Project">
<!-- updated khahn 20090507 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
Eclipse requires that all files are organized in a project. Give the project an arbitrary name. To create the project outside your default workspace, deselect the option to use the default location, and browse to a different location.  
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.4.html" label="Create a new project"/>
</context>

<context id="NewReportWizard_ID" title="New Report - Create a new report">
<!-- updated khahn 20090507 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
After creating a project or selecting an existing project, create a new report.  Select a parent folder from the list of project folders. Specify the file name of the report.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.5.html" label="Create a new report"/>
</context>

<context id="NewReportCopyWizard_ID" title="New Report - Select a report to copy">
<!-- updated khahn 20090507 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
Create a report based on a template or start from a blank report.  
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.5.html" label="Create a new report"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_NewDataSource_ID" title="New Data Source - Select a Data Source Type or Choose a Connection Profile">
<!-- updated khahn 20090507 linked 20090604-->
<description>
The data source specifies how the report connects to the database, file, or web service to retrieve data.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.6.html" label="Build a data source"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_Dataset_ID" title="New Data Set">
<!-- updated khahn 20090507 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
A <b>data set</b> is a query that specifies which data to retrieve from the data source. Type a name, or part of a name, to filter the list of data sources. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.7.html" label="Build a data set"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_SQLQuery_Dataset_ID" title="New SQL Select Query">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Per Diana, make a new data set based on a connection profile. I did it and still cannot file this topic. khahn 20090507 Updated 20090613 -->
<description>Create the SQL Select query to retrieve data from the data source. Select and join tables. Specify how to sort data, what data to retrieve and group for aggregations, and the criteria for returning aggregate data. 
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DatasourceProfile_ID" title="Data Source Profile">
<!-- updated khahn 20090507 linked, abbreviated label 20090604 -->
<description>
Specify how to connect the report to a database, file, or web service. The Classic Models data source is preconfigured and ready to use with BIRT.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.3.html" label="How to specify connection information for a data source"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_JDBC_Datasource_ID" title="New JDBC Data Source Profile">
<!-- updated khahn 20090507 linked, abbreviated label 20090604 -->
<!-- SEQUENCE 1: In Data Explorer, right-click a data source, select New. Choose JDBC Data Source. Choose Next.  khahn 20090505 -->
<description>
Specify a driver class, the driver URL, such as jdbc:mysql://localhost/table_name, and the database user name and password.  Optionally, specify the URL to the Java Naming and Directory Interface (JNDI) connection pooling service.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.3.html" label="How to specify connection information for a data source"/>
</context>

<context id="Dialog_JDBC_ManageDrivers_ID" title="Manage JDBC Drivers">
<!-- SEQUENCE: In Data Explorer, right-click a data source, select New. Choose JDBC Data Source. Choose Next. Choose Manage Drivers. TALK TO DIANA ABOUT HER MARKUP: We to describe the add function on the JAR Files tab and on the Drivers tab, you must specify a URL template or the data source will not work. Diana says describe tabs. khahn 20090507 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
On JAR Files, add a driver in JAR file format. On Drivers, type a URL template, such as jdbc:mysql://localhost/table_name. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.4.html" label="How to add a JDBC driver"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_JDBCDataset_ID" title="Query">
<!-- updated khahn 20090428 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
Complete the SELECT statement to define an SQL query. Type the entire statement or double-click available items, such as tables and fields, to complete the query definition. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.7.html" label="Build a data set"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_ScriptDataset_ID" title="New Data Set - Output columns">
<!-- Updated using 2.5 Build <2.5.0.v20090423-0630>. khahn 20090505 linked 20090604 -->
<!-- SEQUENCE: Create a scripted data source>New scripted data set>Next  -->
<description>
Define output columns for data in the scripted data source. A <b>scripted data source</b> is a Java object that contains tabular data, retrieved using JavaScript.   
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.5.html" label="How to view and change output columns"/>
</context>

<context id="Dialog_JDBCDriver_ID" title="Edit JDBC Drivers">
<!-- Cannot find this help in 2.5 Build <2.5.0.v20090423-0630>. khahn 20090505 linked 20090604 Need to check anchor name in the link each time we rebuild the help. -->
<description>
Specify the JDBC driver properties for display, including a URL template, such as jdbc:mysql://localhost/table_name.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.4.html#216732" label="Editing a JDBC driver URL template"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_JointDataSet_ID" title="New Data Set - Joint Data Set">
<!-- Updated using 2.5 Build <2.5.0.v20090423-0630>. khahn 20090505 linked 20090604 -->
<!-- SEQUENCE: In Data Explorer, right-click Data Sets>New Joint Data Set -->
<description>
Create a <b>joint data set</b>, which uses data from different data sources or from non-relational data sources. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.7.html" label="How to join data sets"/>
</context>

<context id="Dialog_DatasourceEdit_ID" title="Edit Data Source - Data Source">
<!-- Updated khahn 20090505 linked 20090604 Read about the bug in sequences below. -->
<!-- SEQUENCE 1: In Data Explorer, double-click a data source type, select ?. The first time this topic is displayed you see this topic. Subsequently, a DTP topic, depending on the data source type you selected, is displayed. SEQUENCE 2: Select Property Binding, select ?> khahn 20090505 -->
<description>
Follow on-screen prompts, which vary by data source type, to edit the data source.   
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/connecting.2.1.html" label="Connecting to a Data Source"/>
</context>

<context id="Dialog_DatasetEdit_ID" title="Edit Data Set - Data Set">
<!-- Updated khahn 20090505 linked 20090604 enhanced per Nola 20090616-->
<!-- SEQUENCE: In Data Explorer, double-click a data set. -->
<description>
Edit or view the following attributes of the data set:
- Data Source - Change the data source for the data set. 
- Output Columns - Add an alias or display name for each column that BIRT uses in Data Explorer and in column headings of a table. Specify a display name ID that specifies the resource key.
- Computed Columns - Add the result of an expression to the data set.
- Parameters - Create a data set parameter to filter the result set in a query. At runtime, the data set parameter provides a replacement for the ? parameter marker in the WHERE clause of the query.
- Filters - Filter the data set as an alternative to filtering the data source.
- Property Binding - Bind the data set parameter to the report parameter. Specify a time limit for the query request. Typically, the report parameter prompts the user for a value and passes it to the data set parameter to use in the query.
- Settings - Include all rows in the preview of query results, or limit the number of rows. BIRT ignores this setting when the data set editor preferences specifies fewer rows.
- Preview Results - View column names and field values that the query retrieves from the data source.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.5.html" label="How to view and change output columns"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.6.html" label="How to add a computed field to a data set"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.1.html" label="How to define a data set parameter"/>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSourcePropertyBinding(org_eclipse_birt_report_data_oda_jdbc)_ID" title="Edit Data Source - JDBC Data Source - Property Binding">
<!-- Obsolete not updated.  -->
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a JDBC data source. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Source. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

- JDBC Driver Class: Type an expression for the JDBC driver. This driver specifies the brand of database you use.
- JDBC Driver URL: Type an expression for the URL for the machine that runs the database.
- User Name: Type an expression for the user name you use to access the database.
- Password: Type an expression for the Password for the user name.
- JNDI URL: Type an expression for the URL for the JNDI name you use to access the database.
- Connection Profile Name: Type an expression for the name of the connection profile.
- Connection Profile Store URL: Type an expression for the URL to the location of the connection profile store.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSourcePropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_connectivity_oda_flatfile)_ID" title="Edit Data Source - Flat File Data Source - Property Binding">
<!-- Obsolete not updated. SEQUENCE 1: In Data Explorer, double-click a flat file data source, select ?. The DTP topic is displayed. SEQUENCE 2: Select Property Binding, select ? The Dialog_DatasourceEdit_ID topic is displayed  khahn 20090505 -->
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a flat file data source. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Source. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

- Home Folder: Type an expression for the path to a folder that contains the flat file to use as a data source.
- CSV Type: Type an expression for the data format. Valid values are:
  - CSV for comma-separated values
  - PSV for pipe-separated values
  - SSV for space-separated values
  - TSV for tab-separated values
- Character Set: Type an expression for the character set that the data values use.
- Use First Line as Column Name Indicator: Type an expression for a Boolean value. True indicates that the file provides data field names in its first line. False indicates that the first line does not contain data field names.
- Use Second Line as Data Type Indicator: If the value of Use First Line as Column Name Indicator is false, this field applies to the first line of the flat file, rather than the second line. Type an expression for a Boolean value. True indicates that the file provides data types for the data fields. False indicates that the line does not contain data field types.
- Connection Profile Name: Type an expression for the name of the connection profile.
- Connection Profile Store URL: Type an expression for the URL to the location of the connection profile store.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSourcePropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_enablement_oda_ws)_ID" title="Edit Data Source - Web Service Data Source - Property Binding">
<!-- Obsolete not updated. khahn 20090505 -->
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a web service data source. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Source. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

- SOAP End Point: Leave this field empty if the descriptor defines the end point or if the WSDL does not require a SOAP end point. If your WSDL does require a SOAP end point, type an expression for the URL here.
- Connection Class: If you have written a Java class to perform the connection to and of the WSDL data source, type an expression for the fully qualified path to this class. This class must implement the <code>org.eclipse.datatools.enablement.oda.ws.api.IWSDriver</code> interface.
- Connection Time Out: Type an expression for the length of time, in seconds, to wait for the connection to succeed.
- WSDL URL: Type an expression for the URL for Web Services data that is a network resource.
- Driver ClassPath: If you have a custom driver class, type an expression to list the JAR files or folders to search for the class in Driver Class Path. Separate multiple folders and JAR files with semicolon (;) characters in the normal way.
- Connection Profile Name: Type an expression for the name of the connection profile.
- Connection Profile Store URL: Type an expression for the URL to the location of the connection profile store.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSourcePropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_enablement_oda_xml)_ID" title="Edit Data Source - XML Data Source - Property Binding">
<!-- Obsolete not updated. khahn 20090505 -->
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a XML data source. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Source. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

- XML Data Source File: Type an expression for the full name of the XML file to use as the data source.
- XML Data Source Encoding: Type an expression for the character encoding that the XML data uses.
- XML Data Source Schema File: Type an expression for the full name of the schema to use for the XML file.
- Connection Profile Name: Type an expression for the name of the connection profile.
- Connection Profile Store URL: Type an expression for the URL to the location of the connection profile store.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSetPropertyBinding(org_eclipse_birt_report_data_oda_jdbc)_ID" title="Edit Data Set - JDBC Data Set - Property Binding">
<!-- Obsolete not updated. khahn 20090505 -->
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a JDBC data set. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Set. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

- Query Text: Type an expression for the SQL statement for the query.
- Query Time Out: Type an expression for the length of time, in seconds, to wait for the query to return the first data row.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSetPropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_connectivity_oda_flatfile)_ID" title="Edit Data Set - Flat File Data Set - Property Binding">
<!-- Obsolete not updated. khahn 20090505 -->
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a flat file data set. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Set. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

In Query Text, type an expression for the query. Use the XML source tab in the Report Design Perspective to locate the QueryText element of an existing flat file data set. Use this element as a template for the required syntax.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSetPropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_enablement_oda_ws)_ID" title="Edit Data Set - Web Service Data Set - Property Binding">
<!-- Obsolete not updated. khahn 20090505 -->
<description>
Use this page to define the run-time attributes of a web service data set. Values that you set on this page override the values defined on the other pages of Edit Data Set. You can use JavaScript to build the property binding value, for example, to access the values of report parameters.

- Query Text: Type an expression for the SOAP request template for the query. Use the XML source tab in the Report Design Perspective to locate the QueryText element of an existing web service data set. Use this element as a template for the required syntax.
- XML File: Type an expression for the name of the XML file that contains sample data for the SOAP response.
- Schema File: Type an expression for the name of the XML schema file for the SOAP response on the file system.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Wizard_DataSetPropertyBinding(org_eclipse_datatools_enablement_oda_xml)_ID" title="Edit Data Set - XML Data Set - Property Binding">
<!-- Obsolete not updated. khahn 20090512 -->
<description>
An XML data set does not use any property binding values.
</description>
</context>

<context id="NewTemplateWizard_ID" title="New Template">
<!-- SEQUENCE: File>New>Template. khahn 20090512 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
Create a template to define a straightforward way to use a custom layout and master pages for a suite of reports.  
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.19.1.html" label="Building a Shared Report Development Framework"/>
</context>

<context id="NewLibraryWizard_ID" title="New Library">
<!-- SEQUENCE: File>New>Library. khahn 20090512 linked 20090604 updated 20090609 -->
<description>
Create a library to store common report elements, such as images and styles. Design libraries for sharing among a suite of reports.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.19.1.html" label="Building a Shared Report Development Framework"/>
</context>

<context id="SaveReportAsWizard_ID" title="Save as">
<!-- SEQUENCE: File>SaveAs. updated khahn 20090512 -->
<description>
Save the file by its current name and in its current folder, or specify another file name or location.
</description>
</context>

<context id="PublishTemplateWizard_ID" title="Template properties">
<!-- SEQUENCE: File>New>Template>Next. updated khahn 20090512 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
Specify a template name, and optionally a description. Browse to an image for the template, or choose Finish to accept the default image.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.19.1.html" label="Building a Shared Report Development Framework"/>
</context>

<context id="FormatBuilder_ID" title="Format Builder">
<!-- SEQUENCE: In Data Explorer, expand Report Parameters, then choose the report parameter to edit. Choose Change.  Updated. khahn 20090512 linked 20090616 -->
<description>
A report parameter value appears unformatted in a prompt when the report runs. Reformat the report parameter value using a predefined format, such as currency, or a custom format.  
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.5.html" label="How to format a report parameter value"/>

</context>

<context id="ImportValueDialog_ID" title="Import Values">
<!-- SEQUENCE: In Data Explorer, expand Report Parameters, then double-click the report parameter to edit. For Display type, choose Combo Box, List Box, or Radio Button. Choose Import Values. Updated. khahn 20090512 no relevant link 20090604 -->
<description>
Import values from a data set field to display in the list box, combo box, or as radio buttons. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.1.html" label="Enabling the User to Filter Data"/>

</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderGeneral_ID" title="New Style - General Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style. Updated. khahn 20090512 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
Create a style to apply a set of formats to report elements.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.2.html" label="How to create a style"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderFont_ID" title="New Style - Font Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Font. Updated. khahn 20090512 no relevant link, Diana to fix 20090604 -->
<description>
Set the font properties for the style. The user must have the font installed. 
</description>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderBackground_ID" title="New Style - Background Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Background. Updated. khahn 20090512 link check anchor when we rebuild help 20090604 -->
<description>
Set the cascading style sheet (CSS) background properties for a style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.10.html#138935" label="Background properties in New Style"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderTextBlock_ID" title="New Style - Text Block Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Text Block. Updated. khahn 20090512 no relevant link -->
<description>
Set the cascading style sheet (CSS) text block properties for a style.
</description>

</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderBox_ID" title="New Style - Box Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Box. Updated. no relevant link, Diana  20090612 -->
<description>
Set the cascading style sheet (CSS) box properties for a style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.14.html" label="Resizing margins, borders, and padding of elements"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderBorder_ID" title="New Style - Border Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Border. Updated. khahn 20090512 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
Set the cascading style sheet (CSS) border properties for a style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/grouping.8.10.html" label="Separate each group with a line"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderFormatNumber_ID" title="New Style - Format Number Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Format Number. Updated. khahn 20090512 no relevant links -->
<description>
Set the number formatting for a style.
</description>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderFormatDateTime_ID" title="New Style - Format Date Time Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Format DateTime. Updated. khahn 20090512  -->
<description>
Set the date and time formatting for a style.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/subreport.13.16.html#339726" label="Change the date formats"/>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderFormatString_ID" title="New Style - Format String Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Format String. Updated. khahn 20090512 no relevant link, Diana to fix -->
<description>
Set a string format, such as uppercase, for a style.
</description>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderPageBreak_ID" title="New Style - Page Break Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Page Break. Updated. no relevant link, diana 20090612 -->
<description>
Set page break properties for a style. In Widows and Orphans, specify the mininum number of lines to display at the top or bottom of a page when a section displays text on multiple pages. In Before, specify if a page break is inserted before the element to which the style is applied. In After, specify if a page break is inserted after the element to which the style is applied.
</description>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderMap_ID" title="New Style - Map Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Map. Updated. khahn 20090512 no relevant link, Diana to fix -->
<description>
Set alternate values for a style to display instead of data as it appears in the database. 
</description>
</context>

<context id="StyleBuilderHighlights_ID" title="New Style - Highlights Page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click an empty area in layout editor or a report element such as a label, choose Style>New Style>Highlights. Updated. khahn 20090512 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
Set a formatting rule for a style that defines when and how to change the appearance of an element. Specify a condition, such as row["OrderTotal"] Greater than 50000, and a property, such as color.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.8.html" label="How to create a formatting rule"/>
</context>

<context id="ParameterGroupDialog_ID" title="New Parameter Group">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click Report Parameters and choose New Parameter Group. Updated. khahn 20090512 no relevant link -->
<description>
If you create many parameters, or want the report to prompt for a certain set of parameters, use parameter groups. 
</description>
</context>

<context id="HyperlinkBuilder_ID" title="Hyperlink Options">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Select a label in layout editor, select Hyperlink in property editor, choose the elipsis. Updated. khahn 20090512 no link 20090604 -->
<description>
Define a hyperlink for a data, label, image, or chart element. 
</description>

</context>

<context id="ExpressionBuilder_ID" title="Expression Builder">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Select a table in layout editor, select the Binding tab in property editor, double-click an expression, choose Fx. Updated. khahn 20090602 linked 20090604 -->
<description>
Create expressions using a combination of constants, controls, functions, literal values, field names, and operators that evaluate to a single value.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/ScriptingReference.24.1.html" label="Scripting Reference"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/expressions.html" label="Writing Expressions"/>
</context>

<context id="ParameterDialog_ID" title="New Parameter">
<!-- SEQUENCE: In Data Explorer, right-click Report Parameter, and choose New Parameter. Updated. khahn 20090602 linked 20090604 -->
<description>Define a parameter that prompts a user to provide input when the report runs.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.1.html" label="Enabling the User to Filter Data"/>
</context>

<context id="CascadingParametersDialog_ID" title="New Cascading Parameter">
<!-- SEQUENCE: In Data Explorer, right-click Report Parameter, and choose Cascading Parameter. Updated. no relevant link khahn 20090602 -->
<description>
Define report parameters that have a hierarchical relationship.
</description>
</context>

<context id="ImageBuilder_ID" title="New Image Item">
<!--  SEQUENCE: Drag the image element from the palette, and drop it in the page. updated and linked khahn 20090604 -->
<description>
Specify the location from which to select the image.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.5.html" label="How to insert a linked image"/>
</context>

<context id="TableOptionDialog_ID" title="Insert Table">
<!--  SEQUENCE: Drag a table element from the palette to the layout. updated 20090606 linked khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Insert a Table element, specifying the data set from which to retrieve tabular data. Specify the number of rows between the header and footer rows.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.8.html" label="Lay out the report"/>
</context>

<context id="GridOptionDialog_ID" title="Insert Grid">
<!--  updated 20090606 linked khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Insert a Grid element and use the grid to arrange static elements, such as text and images, within a section.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/subreport.13.14.html" label="Display the subreports next to one another"/>
</context>

<context id="TextEditor_ID" title="Edit Text Item">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Double-click a text element. updated 20090606 linked khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Edit and format a Text element. Select the formatting type, HTML or Plain. Select the type of HTML tags to use, or select Dynamic Text. Select Dynamic Text to embed an expression in the text.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/text.6.1.html" label="Displaying text"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/text.6.2.html" label="How to use a dynamic text element"/>
</context>

<context id="GroupDialog_ID" title="New Group">
<!-- SEQUENCE: right-click in the table and choose <b>Insert Group - Above</b> or <b>Insert Group - Below<  updated 20090608 linked khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Define and configure groups. Grouping data in a report can make the data easier to interpret and use. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/grouping.8.7.html" label="Group customer data by credit limit"/>
</context>

<context id="DataBindingDialog_ID" title="Select Data Binding">
<!--  Obsolete? SEQUENCE: see ColumnBindingDialog_ID. Cannot find this one of two Select Data Binding help topics. updated 20090608 linked khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Bind data columns or expressions to names. Select the appropriate data set and column, and define calculated fields that items inside a list or table can use.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.7.html" label="How to insert images that are stored in a data source"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.1.html" label="Binding data"/>
</context>

<context id="HighlightRuleBuilder_ID" title="New Highlight">
<!-- Select report element, choose Highlights tab in Property Editor. Choose Add. linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090608 -->
<description>
First, specify the condition for formatting a report element. Next, specify the formatting. Select from the common conditions or open expression builder and define a condition. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.8.html" label="How to create a formatting rule"/>
</context>

<context id="Preference_BIRT_BIDI_ID" title="Preferences - Bidirectional Properties page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Window>Preferences>Report Design>Bidirectional Properties -->
<!--  no relevant link khahn 20090605 updated 20090609 -->
<description>Set the default base text direction and design interface orientation for new report designs. To design reports in languages such as English, choose Left to Right. To design reports in languages such as Hebrew, choose Right to Left.  
</description>
</context>

<context id="Preference_BIRT_DataSetEditor_ID" title="Preferences - Data Set Editor page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Window>Preferences>Report Design>Data Set Editor linked khahn 20090605 updated Diana 20090610 Corrected 20090616 -->
<description>Specify how many rows to retrieve from the data source for previewing query results. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.8.html" label="How to change the number of rows that appear in Preview Results"/>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_ElementNames_ID" title="Preferences - Element Names page">
<!--  no relevant link, Diana 20090605 -->
<description>
Assign custom default names to elements that you use in your report. Each name you specify appears in the element's Name property on the General properties page of Property Editor. For example, if you assign CustomerReportTable as the default name for the table element, and you insert three tables in the report, the first table's name is CustomerReportTable, the second table's name is CustomerReportTable1, and the third table's name is CustomerReportTable2.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Preference_BIRT_Library_ID" title="Preferences - Library page">
<!--  no relevant link, Obsolete, no library on preferences list khahn 20090605 -->
<description>Use this page to add or remove libraries.

A BIRT report library is a collection of report components that can be used in a report design. Report components include reusable visual report items, data sources, data sets, parameters, translations and more.

A library is a customizable, pre-defined set of rules that helps a user quickly create a report with a specific look.

A BIRT library includes both formatting information and rules that help you create a report. A library is like a skin for a report; it takes the data, structure, and layout of a report, and applies formatting defined in the library to transform the appearance of the report.

A library can start with a style sheet, a set of common styles to apply to all reports within an application. The library can then add commonly used data sources, reusable components, translated text, images and more.

</description>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_Preview_ID" title="Preferences - Preview page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Window>PReferences>Report Design>PReview linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090610-->
<description>Select a bidirectional text setting to orient text in previews. The Report Designer interface follows the orientation of the text. To preview reports in languages such as English, choose Left to Right. To preview reports in languages such as Hebrew, choose Right to Left. Enable a Scalable Vector Graphics (SVG) device renderer for the chart engine. </description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/localization.20.4.html" label="How to preview a report in a different locale"/>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_PreviewServer_ID" title="Preferences - Preview Server page">
<!--  SEQUENCE: Window>PReferences>Report Design>PReview>Preview Server. Tested link to Web Tools Platform User Guide and it worked last week, but now it does not. no relevant link khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Specify the BIRT server and port values. The default Tomcat server runs under Eclipse and serves report previews to users. 
</description>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_Template_ID" title="Preferences - Template page">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Window>PReferences>Report Design>PReview>Templates linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090610 -->
<description>By default, BIRT stores templates in a location that is not shared. To share report templates, specify a folder that contains your templates.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.19.6.html" label="How to set up a template folder"/>
</context>


<context id="ImportCssStyle_ID" title="Import CSS Styles">
<!-- SEQUENCE: right-click a report. Choose Style>Import CSS Style  linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>Browse to and select a cascading style sheet (CSS) file. Select styles you want from the list of the report’s styles. BIRT renames any incompatible style name, lists the unique name, and imports the styles. Notifications appear about any unsupported CSS syntax contained in the file.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.3.html" label="How to import styles"/>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_CommentTemplate_ID" title="Preferences - Comment Template">
<!--  no relevant link, Diana  20090605 -->
<description>Add a boilerplate comment to every report design you create. The comment appears in a report's Comments page under Properties in Property Editor.
</description>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_Resource_ID" title="Preferences - Resource">
<!--  linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>To share resources with other developers, change the location of resources from your workspace to a shared location. Browse to a shared folder relative to your workspace, or browse the file system. Alternatively, browse Eclipse variables and select a variable that represents a folder, such as eclipse_home. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/localization.20.1.html" label="Localizing text"/>
</context>


<context id="PublishLibraryDialog_ID" title="Publish Library">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Open library, File>Place Library in Resource Folder. no relevant link khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>To share a library, publish it to a resource folder. Change the file name and accept the default folder, or browse to a subfolder of the resource folder.  
</description>
</context>

<context id="ResourceSelectDialog_ID" title="Browse resource folders">
<!-- SEQUENCE: select an item in layout, right-click and choose export to library, type a name, choose OK. no relevant link khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>Choose the arrow to filter the list of resource folders contained in Resource Explorer. Select a resource folder in which to publish the library.
</description>
</context>


<context id="ExportToLibrary_ID" title="Export">
<!--  SEQUENCE: Right-click an element in layout, select Export to Library. no relevant link khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>Type a name for the item you want to export to a library, or choose OK to use the default name.
</description>
</context>


<context id="CreateTemplateReportItem_ID" title="Create Template Report Item">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Right-click the Report Title label of a template, and choose Create Template Report Item.  linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>Provide a name for the report item and instructions for the user about how to use the template.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.19.5.html" label="How to create a template report item"/>
</context>


<context id="AddEditMapRule_ID" title="New or Edit Map Rule">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Choose Map tab>Add. no relevant link khahn 20090605 edited, resource key feature does not seem to work. 20090611 -->
<description>Define rules that map values from a database column to values in a report column. Each map rule contains a condition and a display value. For example, a set of map rules for a gender database column might map the values null, M, and F into display values No data, Male, and Female respectively.
</description>
</context>


<context id="AddEditUserProperties_ID" title="Add or Edit User Properties">
<!--  no relevant link khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>Type a unique name and select a data type to store information, such as state, in any items in a report. User properties can provide indirect access to the JavaScript classes for BIRT event handlers written in Java code.
</description>
</context>

<context id="AddEditNamedExpression_ID" title="New or Edit Named Expressions">
<!--  SEQUENCE: select a data element, in Property Editor, choose Named Expression, choose Add. no relevant link, khahn 20090605 updated 20090610 -->
<description>Give the expression a unique name, such as rowCustomerName. To specify a default value, open the expression builder. Build an expression, such as ["CUSTOMERLASTNAME"] + "," + row["CUSTOMERFIRSTNAME"].
</description>
</context>


<context id="ResourceEditDialog_ID" title="Property Editor - Localization">
<!-- In the layout editor, select the label or text element. In Property Editor, choose Localization. linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>
Assign an existing resource key to a label or text element. Browse to and select a key from the list of keys defined in the report's resource file. Assign a resource file to the report to enable browsing.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/localization.20.2.html" label="How to assign a resource file to a report"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/localization.20.3.html" label="How to assign an existing resource key to a label or text element"/>
</context>


<context id="AddLibraryDialog_ID" title="Add Library">
<!-- Obsolete. SEQUENCE: cannot find this dialog box. I think AddResourceDialog_ID has replaced it.  no relevant link khahn 20090605 not updated. -->
<description>Add a library to the resource folder.
</description>
</context>


<context id="AddResourceDialog_ID" title="Add Resource">
<!-- SEQUENCE: In Resource Explorer, choose Add. linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>Specify the source file by browsing to and selecting a resource, such as a library, an image, or a cascading style sheet (CSS) file. Provide the file name. Browse to and select a shared resource folder if you want to share the resource.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.4.html" label="How to link a CSS file"/>
</context>


<context id="ColumnBindingDialog_ID" title="Select Data Binding">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Drag the image element from the palette, and drop it in report. On Edit Image Item, select Dynamic image. Choose Select Image Data. linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>Bind a column to a report element. Select the data set that contains the column. Select the name of a column to bind to the report element. Add an aggregation to define a calculated field for an element contained in a list or table.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/layout.5.7.html" label="How to insert images that are stored in a data source"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.1.html" label="Binding data"/>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_DataSetEditor_JDBC_ID" title="Preferences - JDBC Data Set">
<!--  no relevant link, Diana 20090612 -->
<description>Specify the maximum number of database schemas and tables to display in Available Items on the Query page of the data set editor.
</description>
</context>

<context id="Preference_BIRT_DataSetEditor_XML_ID" title="Preferences - XML Data Set">
<!--  Obsolete? The only Preferences - XML Data Set dialog I can find in in Preferences>Data Management>Connectivity>XML Data SEt and it does not display this help. no relevant link khahn 20090605 -->
<description>Use this page to control the column mapping page.
</description>
</context>


<context id="Preference_BIRT_CrossTab_ID">
<!--  no relevant link, Diana  20090612 -->
   <description>Set options to control the behavior of the cross tab builder.
   
In Filter Limit, specify the number of values to retrieve from the data source when selecting values for a filter.

In Prompt, select whether to display the informational message about how to create a crosstab element.

You can also choose how the report designer treats unused data bindings after you change the structure of a crosstab.</description>
</context>

<context id="Preference_BIRT_GENERAL_ID">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Window>Preferences>Report Design  no relevant link, Diana  20090612 -->
   <description>Set the appearance of a selected item in the report layout editor.

To display a selected item with an animated highlight, select Enable animated selection.

To display a selected item with a gradient highlight that is not animated, deselect Enable animated selection, then select Enable gradient selection.

To display a selected item with a simple outline with handles, deselect both Enable animated selection and Enable gradient selection.</description>
</context>

<context id="Preference_BIRT_Preview_DATA_ID">
<!--  SEQUENCE: Window>Preference>REport Design>Preview>Data no relevant link, Diana 20090612 -->
   <description>Specify the maximum amount of data that a report displays in the Preview page of the report editor. Reducing any of these values makes the report preview faster. Increasing these values produces a report preview that contains more of the data in your data set.

To display all the rows returned by the data set, select No limits on the number of rows to display. To set the maximum number of rows, type a value in Number of rows to display.

To set the maximum number of rows to display in a group in a table or cross tab, type a value in Member count of each row level to display.

To set the maximum number of columns to display in a horizontal group in a cross tab, type a value in Member count of each column level to display.

To limit the size of a data cube structure in memory, type the  number of megabytes in In-memory cube size.</description>
</context>


<context id="ParameterBindingDialog_ID" title="Dataset Parameter Binding">
<!--  linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>Check or change the binding of a parameter to a data set field. Edit the value that a data set parameter uses for the report item.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/subreport.13.10.html" label="Link the orders subreport to the customers master report"/>
</context>


<context id="NewSectionDialog_ID" title="Insert Element">
<!-- no relevant link, Diana to fix  khahn 20090605 -->
<description>Select an element to insert and choose OK.
</description>
</context>


<context id="DeleteWarningDialog_ID" title="Reference Found">
<!-- SEQUENCE: cannot find one. no relevant link  khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>The report item that you selected to delete is used by other items. This list shows items that are dependent on the item you want to delete. If you delete this item,  remove the dependencies before attempting to run the report.
</description>
</context>


<context id="DimensionBuilderDialog_ID" title="Dimension Builder">
<!-- SEQUENCE: cannot find this topic. no relevant link, not updated. khahn 20090605 -->
<description>In Measure, type the size of the property that you selected to edit. In Units, select the unit of measure for the size. 
</description>
</context>


<context id="HandlerClassSelectionDialog_ID" title="Class Selection">
<!-- SEQUENCE: In Property editor, select Event Handler. Choose Browse. no relevant link  khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->

<description>Choose an event handler from the list of applicable event handlers.
</description>
</context>


<context id="NewResourceFileDialog_ID" title="Browse Resource Files">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Select a library in outline>Place library in resource folder>Browse linked  khahn 20090605 updated 20090611-->

<description>Select a resource file from the available list of resource files in the BIRT resource folder.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/localization.20.2.html" label="How to assign a resource file to a report"/>
</context>


<context id="AddJarResourceFileFolderSelectionDialog_ID" title="Browse Resource Files">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Choose Resources in Property Editor. In Jar files, choose Add. No relevant link   khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>
Select a JAR file from the BIRT resource folder.
</description>
</context>


<context id="DataColumnBindingDialog_ID" title="Data Binding">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Drag data element to layout or double-click an aggregation in layout. BUG: Aggregation Builder and New Data Binding are using the same context ID and topics are not interchangeable. linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090611 -->
<description>
Bind an expression to the selected Data element. Specify a unique display name, a data type, such as String, and an expression, such as new Date(). 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.1.html" label="Binding data"/>
</context>


<context id="DataItemBindingDialog_ID" title="Data Item">
<!-- SEQUENCE: cannot find this topic. linked khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Specify a unique display name, a data type, and an expression that specifies an operation on the data item. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/data_binding.4.2.html" label="How to create a column binding"/>
</context>


<context id="Dialog_PropertyHandle_ID" title="Computed Column/Filter/Parameter">
<!--  linked khahn 20090605 -->
<!-- SEQUENCE: Double-click a data set>select Output Columns or anything except Query>In Define output columns, choose a column >choose Edit> This help topic does not work properly. Deleted most of the original verbage that applied to other selections. updated 20090611 Reverted back to the original verbage, and edited it. khahn 20090616  -->
<description>
Set or modify a property of a data set. 

To create a computed column, provide an arbitrary name and a data type. Specify how to compute the column using an aggregation function or an expression, or both. Specify any filtering required for the computation. 

To create a filter, select a column or build an expression that specifies the data to filter. Select a conditional operator and values for the operation. Use this type of filter when the data source does not support filtering in the query.

To create a parameter to filter the results of a query, provide a name, data type, and direction. Direction can be Input, Output, or Input/Output. Only stored procedures support Output and Input/Output. Provide a default value for the parameter or link it to a report parameter.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/retrieving-data.3.6.html" label="How to add a computed field to a data set"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.1.html" label="How to define a data set parameter"/>
</context>


<context id="DataSetParameterBindingInputDialog_ID" title="Data Set Parameter Binding">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Select data in layout, select Binding tab in property editor, choose Data Set Parameter Binding, select the parameter, choose Edit. linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090612 -->
<description>
Open expression builder and build an expression that defines the query for the data set parameter

BIRT supports two types of parameters, report and data set. You typically define both types in master-detail report design. One query defines a report parameter. Another defines a data set operation that uses results of the first query at run time.  
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/subreport.13.10.html" label="Link the orders subreport to the customers master report"/>
</context>

<context id="AddEditSortkey_ID" title="Sort Key">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Select a table. Choose the Sorting tab, choose Add. linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090612 -->
<description>
Create or edit a sort key for this report item. In Key, select a data field on which to sort. Alternatively, open expression builder and create a sorting condition. Specify the sorting direction, ascending or descending.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/getstarted.1.9.html" label="Sort the data"/>
</context>

<context id="AddEditFilterCondition_ID" title="Filter Condition">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Select a table. Choose Filters tab.  linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090612 -->
<description>
To specify the data to retrieve from the data source, open expression builder and build a filter condition. Alternatively, select a data field, a conditional operator, such as Between, and values for the operation.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/aggregate.9.2.html" label="How to display aggregate data"/>
</context>

<context id="ThumbnailBuilder_ID" title="Thumbnail Builder">
<!--  SEQUENCE: Open template, In Outline, select report root. In property editor-General, next to Thumbnail,choose . . . linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090613 -->
<description>
Generate a thumbnail that resembles the report, browse to a thumbnail on the file system, or use a thumbnail in the eclipse workspace.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/SharedWorking.19.7.html" label="How to publish a template"/>
</context>

<context id="SelectionChoiceDialog_ID" title="">
<!--  SEQUENCE: right-click Report Parameters in Data Explorer and choose New Parameter. In Display Type, choose list box, combo box, or radio button. Choose New. khahn 20090605 updated 20090613 -->
<description>
Specify the display text and value of the parameter.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/parameter.12.4.html" label="How to specify static report parameter values"/> 
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderDataSetSelectionPage_ID" title="Data Set Selection Page ">
<!--  SEQUENCE: In Data Explorer, double-click a data cube. Choose Dataset. Choose ? linked khahn 20090616 -->
<description>
Select a data set to go into the group or summary categories.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.6.html" label="Set up data for the cross tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderGroupsPage_ID" title="Groups Page">
<!--  Cannot find this topic. linked khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Create a group.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.6.html" label="Set up data for the cross tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderLinkGroupsPage_ID" title="Link Groups Page">
<!--  In Data Explorer, double-click a data cube. Choose Link Groups. Choose ? linked khahn 20090616 -->
<description>
Create a group link.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.8.html" label="How to create a multi-dataset cube"/> 
</context>

<context id="LevelPropertyDialog_ID" title="Edit Group Level">
<!-- SEQUENCE: In Cross Tab Builder, double-click a data field name in a group. linked-link turned out to be unrelated. updated khahn 20090613 -->
<description>
To specify user-defined values for row and column headings for this dimension, choose Static. To specify values from the data source for row and column headings, choose Dynamic. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.6.html" label="Set up data for the cross tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="MeasureDialog_ID" title="Summary Field Properties">
<!--  SEQUENCE: In Data Explorer, select cube, select Groups and Summaries. Select a summary field, select add. no relevant link, Diana 20090612 -->
<description>
Edit the properties of the summary field. When you drag an item from Available Fields to create a new summary field, the cube builder uses default values for the summary field's name, aggregate function, data type, and expression. You can change any of these values.
</description>
</context>

<context id="AddEditSubTotal_ID" title="Subtotal">
<!--  SEQUENCE: Select the cross tab. Choose Row Area in Property Editor. Choose Sub Totals. Select Data Field. Choose Edit. khahn 20090605 updated 20090613 -->
<description>
Add a subtotal to a row or column in a cross tab, or edit an existing subtotal. Specify a data field and an aggregate function.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.8.html" label="Add grand totals"/> 
</context>

<context id="AddEditGrandTotal_ID" title="Grand Total">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Select the cross tab. Choose Row Area in Property Editor. Choose Grand Totals. Select Data Field. Choose Edit. linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090613 -->
<description>
Add a grand total to a row or column in a cross tab, or edit an existing grand total. Specify a data field and an aggregate function.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.8.html" label="Add grand totals"/> 
</context>

<context id="AddEditPageBreakDialog_ID" title="Page Break">
<!--  no relevant link, Diana 20090612 -->
<description>
Add a page break before or after a group level in the cross tab. Alternatively, add a page break after a fixed number of columns in a group by typing a value in Page Break Interval.
</description>

</context>

<context id="CrossTabFilterConditionBuilder_ID" title="Filter Condition">
<!--  Diana 20090612 -->
<description>
Create or edit a filter condition to limit the data that the cross tab displays. You can filter on any dimension (group), dimension level, or measure.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.12.html" label="How to filter data at the cross tab level"/>
</context>

<context id="CrossTabSorterBuilder_ID" title="sort Key">
<!--  Diana  20090612 -->
<description>
Create or edit a sort condition to sort the cross tab data in a different order. 
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.11.html" label="How to sort cross tab data"/>
</context>

<context id="CrossTabFilterSelectValueDialog_ID" title="Select Value">
<!--  The help does not display the decription in contexts.xml. It displays  The context help for this user interface element could not be found.  Case of mismatched ID? no relevant link khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Select a value from the list to filter the cross tab group.
</description>

</context>

<context id="CrossTabShowSummaryFieldDialog_ID" title="Show Summary Field">
<!--  SEQUENCE: Cannot find this topic. linked khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Show or hide a summary field on a crosstab's group level.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.6.html" label="Set up data for the cross tab"/> 
</context>

<context id="CrossTabLevelViewDialog_ID" title="Show Hide Group Level">
<!-- SEQUENCE: Double-click a group in layout. Diana 20090612 -->
<description>
Select the dimension levels to display or hide. You can skip levels. For example, if there are three levels, you can display the first and the third levels and skip the second.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/crosstab.17.9.html" label="How to display or hide levels"/> 
</context>

<context id="CrossTabAggregationDialog_ID" title="Totals">
<!--  SEQUENCE: From the context menu of a group icon in cross tab, choose Totals. linked updated khahn 20090613 -->
<description>
To hide or display sums, deselect or select subtotals and grand totals in the cross tab. To show sums as text or as a chart, click a row. From the drop-down menu, make a selection. To specify the position of the sum relative to other members in a group, click the sum. From the drop-down menu, select Before or After.  
</description>
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderGroupDialog_ID" title="Group Level">
<!--  no relevant link Diana 20090612 -->
<description>
Select the group levels to include in the cube.
</description>

</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderDateLevelDialog_ID" title="Edit Date Level">
<!--  no relevant link  Diana 20090612 -->
<description>
Edit the properties of the date group.
</description>
</context>

<context id="CubeBuilderFilterListDialog_ID" title="Filter">
<!--  SEQUENCE: drag cube to layout editor. In Data Set Selection, choose Filter. Diana 20090612 -->
<description>
Create, edit, or delete a filter that limits the data rows that the cube uses.
</description>
</context>

<context id="AddCSSDialog_ID" title="Add CSS File">
<!--  Obsolete? Cannot find this topic. I think it has been replaced by AddResourceDialog_ID linked khahn 20090605 -->
<description>
Add a cascading style sheet (CSS) file as a resource.
- Type a file name or browse to an existing CSS file.
- Accept the default or type a new name to save the file in the project.
- Browse to a folder to save the CSS file.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.4.html" label="How to link a CSS file"/> 
</context>

<context id="PublishCSSDialog_ID" title="Publish CSS File">
<!--  Obsolete? cannot find this dialog. In previous releases, there was an  Add CSS File  option and a  Add CSS File  dialog. In the current release, it is Add Resource no relevant link diana 20090612 -->
<description>
Publish a cascading style sheet (CSS) file to the resource folder.
</description>
</context>

<context id="UseCssInReportDialog_ID" title="Use CSS">
<!--  linked khahn 20090605 updated 20090612 -->
<description>
Select a cascading style sheet (CSS) file from the list of CSS styles. If your selection includes any CSS styles that are invalid in BIRT, a notification appears.
</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/format.7.4.html" label="How to link a CSS file"/> 
</context>

</contexts>
