<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?NLS type="org.eclipse.help.contexts"?>

<contexts>
<context id="dummy_outer_container" title="BIRT contexts">
<description>Contexts for items identified by Actuate, 3/06</description>
</context>
<context id="NewReportProjectWizard_ID" title="New Report Project">
<description>Use this dialog box to specify a project name for the new report project. For the project contents, you can either choose to use the default location or specify an alternate location.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="NewReportWizard_ID" title="New Report - Create a new report">
<description>Use this page to specify a parent folder and a file name for a new report.

If you created a project for the new report, you can select it as the parent folder.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="NewReportCopyWizard_ID" title="New Report - Select a report to copy">
<description>Use this page to select a blank report, one of the report templates that are provided with the copy, or a previously created report, and then click <b>Finish</b>.

When you highlight a report template, a preview of the report is displayed to the right.

If you select "Show Report Creation Cheat Sheet," the corresponding cheat sheet will be displayed, if one is available, when you click <b>Finish</b>.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_NewDataSource_ID" title="New Data Source - Select a Data Source Type or Choose a Connection&#10;Profile">
<description>Use this page to select the type of data source that you want to include in your report, then specify the name of the data source.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_Dataset_ID" title="New Data Set">
<description>Use this page to specify a name for the data set, the source of the data, and the data set type.

A <b>data set</b> is a query that specifies the data to retrieve from the data source.

The data set type indicates the type of query. For example, if your report connects to a JDBC data source, you use a SQL SELECT statement to specify the data to retrieve.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_DatasourceProfile_ID" title="Data Source Profile">
<description>This screen displays a profile of the selected database.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_JDBC_Datasource_ID" title="New JDBC Data Source Profile">
<description>Use this dialog box to define a new JDBC data source.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Dialog_JDBC_ManageDrivers_ID" title="Manage JDBC Drivers">
<description>Use this dialog box to manage the available JDBC drivers and to add new ones.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_XML_Datasource_ID" title="New XML File Data Source Profile">
<description>Use this dialog box to define an XML file data source.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_FlatfileDatasource_ID" title="New Flat File Data Source Profile">
<description>Use this dialog box to define the profile for a new flat file



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_ConnectionProfile_ID" title="New Data Source - Select a Connection Profile">
<description>Use this dialog box to select a connection profile for creating a data source.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_JDBCDataset_ID" title="Query">
<description>Use this dialog box to define an SQL query.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_XMLSample_ID" title="XML DataSet">
<description>Use this dialog box to specify a sample XML source for data preview.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_XMLXPath_ID" title="Table Mapping">
<description>Use this dialog box to map a table.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Dialog_XPathExpression_ID" title="Select or edit the XPath expression">
<description>Use this dialog box to specify the XPath expression to be used.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_XML_ColumnMapping_ID" title="Column Mapping">
<description>Use this page to map XML elements to columns.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Dialog_ColumnMapping_ID" title="Column Mapping">
<description>Use this dialog box to map a column to an XPath expression.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_ScriptDataset_ID" title="New Data Set - Output columns">
<description>Use this page to define output columns.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Dialog_SelectTableColumn_ID" title="Select Table - Select Column">
<description>Use this dialog box to select columns for the data set.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Dialog_JDBCDriver_ID" title="Edit JDBC Drivers">
<description>Use this dialog box to specify the JDBC driver properties for display.

Enter a name to be displayed for this driver in the driver manager, and the syntax suggestion to be displayed for this driver in New Data Source.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Wizard_JointDataSet_ID" title="New Data Set - Joint Data Set">
<description>Use this page to define a joint data set by associating data sets and columns.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Dialog_DatasourceEdit_ID" title="Edit Data Source - Data Source">
<description>Use this dialog box to enter URLs for the data source and schema.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Dialog_DatasetEdit_ID" title="Edit Data Set - Data Set">
<description>Use this dialog box to define the attributes of a data set.

A <b>data set</b> is a query that specifies the data to retrieve from the data source.

Selecting an item in the left pane of the dialog box has the following results:

  - Query - allows you to specify the data to retrieve.
  - Data Source - allows you to change the data source you specified in the <b>New Data Set</b> dialog box.
  - Preview - displays a preview of the items that you selected in your query.
  - Computed Columns - allows you to add computed fields to an existing data set.
  - Parameters - allows you to create data set parameters.
  - Filters - allows you to define filters to be applied at the data-set level.
  - Output Columns - allows you to verify and change the columns to be output.
  - Property Binding - allows you to verify and change binding of properties.
  - Cache Preference - allows you to set data-set caching options.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="NewTemplateWizard_ID" title="New Template">
<description>Use this wizard to define a new template for reports.

This type of file provides a structure for a standard report layout.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="NewLibraryWizard_ID" title="New Library">
<description>Use this page to specify a parent folder and a file name for a new library.

This type of file stores customized report elements such as data sources, data sets, visual report items, and styles. Include a library in a report design to access the customized report elements

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="SaveReportAsWizard_ID" title="Save as">
<description>Use this dialog box to specify the filename and location for the file that you are saving.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="PublishTemplateWizard_ID" title="Template properties">
<description>Use this dialog box to specify file name, description, and template image.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="FormatBuilder_ID" title="Format Builder">
<description>Use this dialog box to control the formatting of strings.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="ImportValueDialog_ID" title="Import Values">
<description>Use this dialog box to import values into your report.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderGeneral_ID" title="New Style - General Page">
<description>Use this page to apply a style for to the report element that you selected in the layout editor. Use this page also to define a new style; you can apply the style at this time, but you do not need to.

On the General page, specify one of the following settings:

  - To apply an existing set of style properties to the report element, select <b>Predefined Style</b> and select a style from the drop-down list.
  - To create a user-named style, specify a unique descriptive name for <b>Custom Style</b>. Make sure the name is not the same as any of the predefined style names. If you specify a name that is the same as a predefined style, your custom style takes precedence, and you will no longer be able to use the predefined style to apply cascading styles.

Note that the left side of this dialog box displays property categories. The right side displays the properties for the category you select.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderFont_ID" title="New Style - Font Page">
<description>Use this page for specifying font information for the style.

Note that the left side of this dialog box displays property categories. The right side displays the properties for the category you select.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderBackground_ID" title="New Style - Background Page">
<description>Use this page to specify background information for the style.</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderTextBlock_ID" title="New Style - Text Block Page">
<description>Use this page to specify text block information for the style.</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderBox_ID" title="New Style - Box Page">
<description>Use this page to specify box information for the style.</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderBorder_ID" title="New Style - Border Page">
<description>Use this page to specify border information for the style.</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderFormatNumber_ID" title="New Style - Format Number Page">
<description>Use this page to specify number formatting for the style.</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderFormatDateTime_ID" title="New Style - Format Date Time Page">
<description>Use this page to specify date and time formats for the style.</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderFormatString_ID" title="New Style - Format String Page">
<description>Use this page to specify string format information for the style.</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderPageBreak_ID" title="New Style - Page Break Page">
<description>Use this page to specify page break information for the style.</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderMap_ID" title="New Style - Map Page">
<description>Use this page to specify map information for the style.</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="StyleBuilderHighlights_ID" title="New Style - Highlights Page">
<description>Use this page to specify highlighting information for the style.</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="ParameterGroupDialog_ID" title="New Parameter Group">
<description>Use this dialog box to create a visual grouping of parameters.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-23-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="HyperlinkBuilder_ID" title="Hyperlink Options">
<description>Use this page to define a link to another location

There are three major kinds of links:

  - A hyperlink to an external web site, e-mail system, and so forthThe Hyperlink property returns a standard web-style link with http: or mailto: prefix. Expression hyperlinks can include special BIRT features, but only as encoded into a URL. If the link specifies a target within the document, encode that target within the URL as defined by target document type, as in the URL, <b>http://MyPage.com/docs/myDoc.html#myTarget</b>.


  - A bookmark to a location within the report as specified by a bookmark.Use the Bookmark property of a report item to create the target bookmark.


  - A drill-though to a location within another report as specified by a bookmark.The drill-though link can link to an existing report, or request to run a new report. It can optionally include:

    - Parameters to pass when creating a new report.
    - A location within the target report as specified by a search.
    - A location within the target report as specified by a bookmark.




</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-23-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="ExpressionBuilder_ID" title="Expression Builder">
<description>Use this dialog box to create expressions for any purpose that your report requires.

For example, you can create a computed field in your report layout, or create aggregate expressions to display summary information.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-05-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-10-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="ParameterDialog_ID" title="New Parameter">
<description>Use this dialog box to create a report parameter to allow users to filter your report. The report parameter prompts users to specify values that determine the rows to retrieve.



Specify the following basic properties:

  - For Name, type a name for the parameter. If you do not specify a value for Prompt text (the next property), the report user sees the Name value as the parameter prompt.
  - For Type, select a data type for the parameter.The data type you select does not have to match the data type of the field in the data source. Values in an orderID field, for example, could be stored as integers in the database but the report parameter associated with this field can be of decimal or string type. The data type you select for the report parameter determines the formatting options available should you choose to provide a default value or a list of values for the report parameter.

For date fields, you can select either Date Time or String. Specifying string data type provides more flexibility for the user to specify dates in a variety of formats. The user can enter, for example, 02/04/2004, 2/4/04, or Feb 4, 2004. The trade-off is that you cannot use date and time formats to change how dates are displayed should you choose to provide the user with a list of date values.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-13-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="CascadingParametersDialog_ID" title="New Cascading Parameter">
<description>Use this dialog box to define a cascading parameter group.

A parameter group is a visual grouping of dynamic parameters. When the value of a particular parameter in the group depends on the value of another parameter, the parameter group is a cascading parameter group.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-23-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="ImageBuilder_ID" title="New Image Item">
<description>Use this dialog box to insert an image directly on the page or in any container element.

In you are inserting an linked image, select the <b>Linked image</b> button. Under Enter URI, specify the location of the image file. Enclose the URI in double quotation marks (" ").

In you are inserting an embedded image, select the <b>Embedded image</b> button, then click <b>Add Image</b> to select the image that you want to embed.

Typically, you insert data source images in the detail row of a table to display all the pictures stored in the data source. If you are entering an image that is stored in a data source, select the <b>Dynamic image</b> button, then click <b>Binding</b> to specify the data source.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-05-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="TableOptionDialog_ID" title="Insert Table">
<description>Use this dialog box to insert a Table element.

The Table element presents data from a data set in using a tabular layout. The columns property is optional and defines the columns. The header appears at the top of the table, and on each new page. The table can contain groups. (Right-click in the table that you inserted and click <b>Insert Group</b>.) The footer displays totals and appears at the bottom of the table. The detail appears for every row in the data set.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-23-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="TextEditor_ID" title="Edit Text Item">
<description>Use this dialog box to edit and format Text elements.

The Text element displays a multi-line block of text defined within the report. This element can contain embedded formatting and value expressions.

The Text item allows the report developer to provide the text as part of the report design. Text can be in HTML or plain text format and can be localized. HTML text can contain placeholders for data and expressions, much like the mail merge feature of a word processing program.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-23-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="GroupDialog_ID" title="New Group">
<description>Use this dialog box to define and configure groups.

Grouping data in a report can make the data easier to interpret and use. For example, you can group customer data by credit limit.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-09-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="DataBindingDialog_ID" title="Data Binding">
<description>Use this dialog box to specify the data set that contains the images that you want to insert.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-05-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="HighlightRuleBuilder_ID" title="New Highlight">
<description>Use this dialog box specify the condition, or rule, for applying a particular format to the report element.

The dialog box helps you specify the If and Then parts of the rule by breaking them down to more specific parts.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_DataSetEditor_ID" title="Preferences - Data Set Editor page">
<description>Use this page to control how the Data Set Editor displays SQL queries and previews reports.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-04-01.html" label="Retrieving data"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_ElementNames_ID" title="Preferences - Element Names page">
<description>Use this page to assign default names to elements of the Report Object Model (ROM).



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-23-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_Library_ID" title="Preferences - Library page">
<description>Use this page to add or remove libraries.

A BIRT report library is a collection of report components that can be used in a report design. Report components include reusable visual report items, data sources, data sets, parameters, translations and more.

A library is a customizable, pre-defined set of rules that helps a user quickly create a report with a specific look.

A BIRT library includes both formatting information and rules that help you the developer create a report. A library is like a "skin" for a report; it takes the data, structure and layout of a report and applies formatting defined in the library to transform the report's appearance.

A library may start with a "style sheet": a set of common styles to apply to all reports within an application. The library can then add commonly used data sources, reusable components, translated text, images and more.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_Preview_ID" title="Preferences - Preview page">
<description>Use this page to control how reports are previewed in web browsers.

To add a browser, select Custom Browser and enter the command to open it.

You can enable an SVG device renderer for the chart engine. This reference implementation (located in the org.eclipse.birt.chart.device.svg plug-in) defines basic SVG drawing primitives based on the SVG 1.1 specification.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-04-01.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_PreviewServer_ID" title="Preferences - Preview Server page">
<description>Use this page to set up an internal application server to preview your reports.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.wst.server.ui.doc.user" href="../org.eclipse.wst.server.ui.doc.user/topics/twcrtins.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_Template_ID" title="Preferences - Template page">
<description>Use this page to specify the folder that contains your templates.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="ImportCssStyle_ID" title="Import CSS Styles">
<description>Use this dialog box to import CSS styles into your report design.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-07-01.html" label="Formatting report content"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_CommentTemplate_ID" title="Preferences - Comment Template">
<description>Use this page to specify a comment to be added when you create a report design.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-02-1.html" label="Learning the basics"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_Resource_ID" title="Preferences - Resource">
<description>Use this page to select the default Resource Folder to use for the Library Explorer.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-20-1.html" label="Localizing text"/>
</context>
<context id="PublishLibraryDialog_ID" title="Publish Library">
<description>Use this dialog box to publish a library to a resource folder.

Publishing a library makes it available for reuse.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="Building a shared report development framework"/>
</context>
<context id="ResourceSelectDialog_ID" title="Browse resource folders">
<description>Use this dialog box to select the resource file to use for publishing the library.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="Building a shared report development framework"/>
</context>
<context id="ExportToLibrary_ID" title="Export">
<description>Use this dialog box to export a report design to a library.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="Building a shared report development framework"/>
</context>
<context id="CreateTemplateReportItem_ID" title="Create Template Report Item">
<description>Use this dialog box to define the properties of template report items.

Template report items are items that you intend report developers to modify for new report designs. Provide the necessary information about making modifications in the Instructions field.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="Building a shared report development framework"/>
</context>
<context id="AddEditMapRule_ID" title="New or Edit Map Rule">
<description>Use this dialog box to define map rules.

Map rules define the rules for mapping values in a database column to values in a report column. Each map rule contains a condition and a display value. For example, a set of map rules for a gender database column might map the values null, M, and F into display values No data, Male, and Female respectively.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-23-01.html" label="Report Object Model reference"/>
</context>
<context id="AddEditUserProperties_ID" title="Add or Edit User Properties">
<description>Use this dialog box to specify user properties for BIRT classes.

User properties can provide indirect access to the BIRT JavaScript classes for BIRT event handlers written in Java code.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-22-1.html" label="Scripting reference"/>
</context>
<context id="AddEditNamedExpression_ID" title="New or Edit Named Expressions">
<description>Use this dialog box to define named expressions.

The name facilitates reuse.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="A related topic"/>
</context>
<context id="ResourceEditDialog_ID" title="Property Editor - Label">
<description>Use this page to define localization properties.

To do this, click the " <b>. . .</b> " button.

Note that you must assign a resource file to the report before you can define localization properties. The " <b>. . .</b> " button is not active until a resource file is assigned.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-20-1.html" label="Localizing text"/>
</context>
<context id="AddLibraryDialog_ID" title="Add Library">
<description>Use this dialog box to add a library to the resource folder.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-19-1.html" label="Building a shared report development framework"/>
</context>
<context id="ColumnBindingDialog_ID" title="Select Data Binding">
<description>Use this dialog box to bind data to columns in a data set.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-10-1.html" label="Aggregating data"/>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-13-1.html" label="Enabling the user to filter data"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_DataSetEditor_JDBC_ID" title="Preferences - JDBC Data Set">
<description>Use this page to control the query page display.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-04-01.html" label="Retrieving data"/>
</context>
<context id="Preference_BIRT_DataSetEditor_XML_ID" title="Preferences - XML Data Set">
<description>Use this page to control the column mapping page.



</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-04-01.html" label="Retrieving data"/>
</context>
<context id="ParameterBindingDialog_ID" title="Dataset Parameter Binding">
<description>This dialog box allows you to verify parameter bindings.

Use the "Value" column to check or change the report parameter to which the data set parameter is bound.

</description>
<topic filter="plugin=org.eclipse.birt.doc" href="../org.eclipse.birt.doc/birt/birt-13-1.html" label="Enabling the user to filter data"/>
</context>
</contexts>
